growfruitandveg.co.uk 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy | Aceville

## Aceville Publications Ltd Privacy Policy

Aceville Publications Ltd (APL) has created this statement to demonstrate our commitment to protecting your personal information and privacy, to explain how we collect information and to explain how we use the information we collect about our website users. When you provide this information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with the laws concerning the protection of personal information covered under “the GDPR”.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement please address them to [legal.notices@aceville.com](mailto:legal.notices@aceville.com)

### 1\. Our Data promise to you

This privacy statement refers to Aceville Publications (hereafter ‘APL’) and the Aceville Publications Ltd Website’s (www.aceville.com– hereafter ‘APL Website’) It also refers to and covers any usage of the Aceville brand websites and does not necessarily reflect the use of data gathered on subscribers to the print editions of magazine titles published by Aceville Publications Ltd or those who have taken advantage of Aceville Publications Ltd advertising promotions unrelated to the APL Website.

This statement is subject to change at any time. The way we use any information will be subject to the privacy statement that is current when that information is gathered. Please check this page regularly to see any changes. This policy is effective from 1st August 2018. 

### 2\. What we collect

APL collects both personal data and anonymous data when you send us information or when you visit one of our websites. When we talk about Personal data we mean any information that can identify you as an individual, such as your name and postal address. Anonymous Data does not identify you as a person but it might be used in aggregate for example when you participate in a survey.

### 3\. Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. All our Websites use SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption for all financial transactions (e.g. subscribing to our magazine titles using our magazinestoyou.com website). 

### 4\. How we collect and use information:

#### Cookies

Cookies are short strings of text sent to your browser and stored by your computer. Most commercial web sites use cookies. We use cookies to remember your preferences and to reference information about the time and extent of your use of the APL Websites. We use this information for purposes of system administration and to track potential abuse of our terms and conditions of use. We also use this information in an aggregated form for purposes of marketing and as information to potential advertisers and subscribers. We do not use this information in any way that is personally identifying.

We also use cookies for authentication and to remember the logged-in status of registered users and subscribers who use our extended subscriber services.

Most browsers have ‘preference’ settings which alert you when cookies are being received and allow you to reject them before they are stored or delete them after they have been stored. If you choose to reject cookies you will still be able to use the APL Websites, but functionality may be reduced and subscribers may be unable to use our extended subscriber or member services or view subscriber-only and member-only content.

We may remarket your information. Remarketing is a way for us to connect with users, based upon your past interactions with APL Websites. Third-party marketing vendors may be hired by the APL to perform remarketing services. As a result, third-party vendors, including Google, may show APL ads on sites on the internet. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to the APL’s websites.

To customize your Google Display Network ads [click here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb). To find out more about how Google uses any data it collects please visit [policies.google.com/technologies/ads](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

#### IP address

Your IP address is a numeric code which is assigned to your computer every time you connect to the internet. Typically for home users it will not identify your computer exactly but will identify the service provider via whom you connect to the internet. We use aggregated IP address information to compile reports on the demographics of the usage of the APL Websites for purposes of system administration, marketing, as information to potential advertisers and subscribers, and to track potential abuse of our terms and conditions of use. We do not use IP address information in a form that is personally identifiable except where the users of that IP address have been responsible for violation of our terms and conditions of use.

#### Subscriptions, sales and other services

When you use the APL Websites to subscribe to the any of our print magazine products, to purchase goods and services, or to update your subscription data, we will need you to provide certain information which enables you to be identified as an individual (name, address, email, credit card details, direct debit details and so on). This information is necessary for us to process your order or update your details.

To enable us to improve our products and services for your benefit we may, providing we have your permission, contact you to ask if you wish to participate in our customer research programme. This may include an invite to join website usability testing which helps us to find ways to improve our website. You will always have the option to ignore the request or to decline.

Your email address will be used to provide you with email updates from ourselves and our carefully selected partners containing special offers, new services and other news. You may unsubscribe at any time by following the link at the bottom of each email.

We would also like to keep you informed about our products and services by post and telephone. You will have the option to agree to this at the time of interaction.

We may associate information referenced by cookies with personal information which you provide to us online. We will not disclose your personal information to third parties except in the following cases:

(1) When it is necessary to provide you with a service you have requested.

(2) Under circumstances required by law: when we believe in good faith that a law or legal process requires it or where we believe disclosure is necessary to protect or enforce our rights, the rights of our contributors whose copyright material is under our control, or the rights of other users of APL websites Website whose personal information is under our control.

#### Newsletter, Email and information sign up

If you sign up for any newsletter or email service we might offer on any of the APL Websites we will hold your email address securely in a list. Our email messages will provide you with email updates from ourselves and our carefully selected partners containing special offers, new services and other news. We will make sure that each newsletter carries information about how to opt out of the list and how to remove your name from the list so that you will be able to choose to stop receiving the email at any time if you so wish.

#### Public Forums

In the future we may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to users of APL’s Websites. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. Your participation in any public forum which we provide is subject to the APL’s terms and conditions of use.

#### Advertisers and Commercial Associates

APL’s Websites contains advertisements and promotional links to web sites operated by third parties. While we would never knowingly link to a site which we believed to be trading in bad faith, APL is not responsible for the content of these web sites and we take no responsibility for the content, privacy practices, goods or services offered by these sites. Specific provisions in the APL’s Website’s terms and conditions of use apply to the content of all advertisements and access to all promotional linked websites.

#### Contextual links

Articles on the APL’s Website’s sometimes contain links to third party websites. These links, provided by contributors to Aceville Publications Ltd, are provided on a contextual basis and are relevant to the essays in which they appear. Aceville Publications are not responsible for the content, business practices or privacy practices of such websites. Specific provisions in the Aceville Publications Website’s terms and conditions of use apply to use of these links.

#### Do we share that data with any other companies?

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy or in the data collection statements that will always be visible when we collect your information and where we give you the opportunity to select your preferences, we may release your data to external companies that we use to process your orders, to supply you with a prize in the event you win a competition, or charge your credit card, for instance. Every supplier we use has to go through a rigorous up-front process to ensure that their processes are at least as good as our own, and they are required to sign a contract that defines what their responsibilities and liabilities are. We make site visits regularly whether our suppliers are in the UK, the EEA or outside the EEA, where we require an EU approved model contract to be signed.

However, you expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Data with those suppliers with whom we contract in order to provide services to you, otherwise we may not be able to provide the level of service that we know you'll require.

If you send in a comment, we may post it on our site or use it as a testimonial without mentioning your full name or publishing any information that would identify you. Furthermore, in some circumstances we may display some of your information such as your username. Others may be able to see your personal data if you post any information on bulletin boards or forums and may be used to send you unsolicited communications over which we have no control.

We may share some of your information with advertisers, ad servers and ad networks to deliver targeted advertising both on our websites and on selected partner websites but this will not include any information which directly identifies you. However, by interacting with or viewing an advert, you should be aware that the third party may make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the advert.

These activities may involve the use of cookies and other similar technologies. To learn more or to see how you can opt out of targeted advertising, for more information please read our Cookie Policy.

Please take care when using social networking sites to which we may invite you to join that you do not disclose anything that you might later wish to retract.

There are certain times when we may be legally required to disclose your data in good faith where it is required by law or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us, or where we have a requirement to protect or defend the rights of Aceville Publications or any users of our servers. We will always ensure that those requesting the information have the legal right to do so.

If another company should acquire any of our companies or our assets, including our database, that company will have the right of possession to the Personal Data collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations formerly attributable to us and will use the data in line with the terms under which you submitted it or as described in this Privacy Policy.

This site also occasionally uses Hotjar to monitor user behaviour in order to improve our services to you. To disable this tracking please visit: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out> \- We delete personal data as soon as it’s processed.

#### Telephone and Mailing Preference Services

The Telephone Preference Service (TPS), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (CTPS) and the Mailing Preference Service (MPS) allow you to choose to opt out of unsolicited marketing. However, if you are registered on any of the preference services, which are general opt-out registers, you may still receive marketing communications from us if you have given us your consent previously or if you subsequently give us that consent.

#### **Marketing to Children**

 **

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16 for marketing purposes.

### Using our websites from outside the UK

We may use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. In some circumstances these providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal information than that provided under UK Law. In such circumstances:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

If you would like further information about the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA please contact: [legal.notices@aceville.com](mailto:legal.notices@aceville.com)

### How you can gain access to the personal data we collect about you

Under the GDPR, you have the right to see what information we hold about you and you may ask us to make any changes that you consider necessary to make the information accurate. If you want to apply to see the data we hold about you, write to:

The Data Protection Officer:  
Aceville Publications Ltd  
1, 19, 21/23, 25 Phoenix Court,  
Hawkins Road,  
Colchester,  
Essex,  
CO2 8JY

We will require that you satisfactorily identify yourself to demonstrate your entitlement to view this data. 

### Questions regarding this Privacy Policy

If you have comments or questions related to this Privacy Policy please email [legal.notices@aceville.com](mailto:legal.notices@aceville.com) and we will respond as promptly and as fully as we can.

Complaints will be dealt with by the Data Protection Officer and will be responded to within 30 days. If you are not satisfied with the response you should refer your complaint to the ICO [https://ico.org.uk/concerns](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)

### Accepting this privacy statement

By using the Aceville Publications and associated Brand websites you signify your acceptance of this privacy statement and our terms and conditions of use. If you do not agree, or are not comfortable with any policy in this statement, your only remedy is to not use the APL Website. If you are concerned about any cookies which have already been issued to you by the APL Website, you can delete cookies served to your browser.

If this privacy statement is not accepted in full, use of all the APL Website’s must be terminated immediately.

**
